# Spencer Steadman

steadman@vt.edu

Student in Computer Science & Engineering at Virginia Tech and Independent Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience in iOS mobile app development. Proven success in programming and design with multiple acclaimed iOS apps approved by Apple.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### PONDER TECHNOLOGIES

Richmond, VA

Founder and Lead Developer

Apr 2023-Present

- Spearheaded the creation of "Ponder: Dream Journal," a cutting-edge mobile application designed to help users record, analyze, and understand their dreams.
- Developed a robust full-stack design system, crafting a scalable backend infrastructure that efficiently processes and analyzes user data while maintaining security and privacy standards.
- Implemented state-of-the-art technologies and frameworks to ensure scalability and responsiveness, including Swift 5, SwiftUI, CoreData, and APIs including OpenAI's GPT Large Language Models.

**EMSCO SOLUTIONS** 

IT Consultant

Ashland, VA

Dec 2023–Jan 2024

- Served as a knowledgeable IT Consulting Intern, playing a pivotal role in bridging the gap between colleague ideas and practical software solutions by implementing custom Excel-based applications.
  - Specialized in leveraging advanced features of Excel, including VBA scripts, Power Query, and PivotTables, to enhance operational efficiency across the company.

#### NOVA OF VIRGINIA AQUATICS, INC.

Richmond, VA

Lifeguard

Jun 2021-Present

- Served as a trusted Lifeguard for swim lessons and USA Swimming swim meets
- Had the opportunity to lead guards during low-staffed swim meets

#### **EDUCATION**

#### VIRGINIA TECH

Blacksburg, VA

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science at Virginia Tech's College of Engineering

Aug 2023-Present

### **VOLUNTEERING**

#### THIRD CHURCH RVA

Richmond, VA

Refugee and Immigrant Academic Tutor

Dec 2015-Apr 2023

- Served as a volunteer tutor for over seven years at Third Church RVA, specializing in teaching Christian Arabic students.
- Dedicated to assisting tutorees, including ESL students, with English language learning and general academic support.
- Championed diversity and inclusion by fostering an open and respectful learning environment, ensuring all perspectives were valued and empowered regardless of their background.

## ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Highly Proficient in MS Excel with Visual Basic for Applications, PowerQuery, and PivotTables
- Over 7 years of experience with the Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Premiere Pro, After Effects, Illustrator, Acrobat)
- Over 5 years of experience in programming with languages including Swift, Python, Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, C, and C++ and experience with SwiftUI, UIKit, Flutter, React.js, and Three.js
- Fluent in English and Spanish (7+ Years of Study)